<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-07-14T23:44:07+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title>Rowthiram</title><subtitle>Stay Put. A blog trying to keep you engaged.</subtitle><entry><title>Employee Referral</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/employee-referral/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Employee Referral" /><published>2016-07-14T16:55:35+05:30</published><updated>2016-07-14T16:55:35+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/employee-referral</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/employee-referral/">&lt;p&gt;Employee referrals are few of the most cost effective ways of employee recruitment and the best means to build man power required by the organization. Employee Referral is a simple internal recruitment method to interview and hire more employees through the referrals provided by their existing employees. Even though there are many ways for recruiting employee, 40% of companies opt for referral recruiting and you know why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the top 6 reasons why companies recruit people by reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;save-time&quot;&gt;SAVE TIME!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timing is everything. The recruitment process is small and easy than compared with other methods of recruiting and also people hired by reference start their new position sooner than their counterparts. Referred hires have job satisfaction and stay in the job for longer than the other recruiters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;save-money&quot;&gt;SAVE MONEY!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Referral recruitment is the cheapest way for recruiting so economically it is the best way for recruitment. The company would always go for the way which is economically best&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quality-is-important&quot;&gt;QUALITY IS IMPORTANT&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the respondents feel that the referral recruiting is the best way for finding the best quality employee. With the increased demand for quality service and products, it has become important for companies to hire more skilled and productive employees. Research has shown that the employees who are hired through the various referral schemes are significantly better and more efficient than the ones hired through the other channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;compatible&quot;&gt;COMPATIBLE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Referred hires fit the company culture and values better because the referral already knows one of the employee and the company already. As the candidates who apply through other channels can be from any locality, or field of work, there are higher possibilities of them not being accustomed to the organization’s work environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;immediate-results&quot;&gt;IMMEDIATE RESULTS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the growing unemployment and the demand for a more skilled workforce, employees are the best way of finding some quick leads and almost double the number of hires within a year. The referral bonuses are often lucrative and lead to a higher employee satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a quick and easy way of generating more and more candidates to hire within your organization, employee referral scheme is certainly the best tactic that you can opt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trust-is-all-that-matters&quot;&gt;TRUST IS ALL THAT MATTERS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The employee knows the referral already thus the company would have full trust on the person through referral recruitment because even when the referral cheats the company or any misbehavior tends to happen still the person could be caught through the referred employee&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>priya_dharsini</name></author><category term="employee-referral" /><category term="readability" /><category term="quality" /><summary>Why employee referrals?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;so-simple-sample-image-7.jpg&quot;}" /></entry><entry><title>Welcome to Rowthiram</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/welcome-to-rowthiram/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Rowthiram" /><published>2016-07-14T16:55:35+05:30</published><updated>2016-07-14T16:55:35+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/welcome-to-rowthiram</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/welcome-to-rowthiram/">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Rowthiram!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rowthiram&quot;&gt;Rowthiram&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rowthiram is an initiative to bring in the most recent happenings in Technology. We would be updating the site continuously with more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would also be rolling out many new tutorials and how-to posts to keep you updated over the happenings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay Put.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,
Team Rowthiram&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>preethi_kr</name></author><summary>Welcome to Rowthiram!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;so-simple-sample-image-5.jpg&quot;}" /></entry></feed>
