<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://rowthiram.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://rowthiram.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-04-02T23:29:21+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/</id><title>Rowthiram</title><entry><title>Engineers with Jobs</title><link href="http://rowthiram.com/articles/engineers-with-jobs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Engineers with Jobs" /><published>2017-04-02T13:55:35+05:30</published><updated>2017-04-02T13:55:35+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/articles/engineers-with-jobs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://rowthiram.com/articles/engineers-with-jobs/">&lt;p&gt;For the people who under-rate engineers for what they are.
To everyone out there who judge engineers for taking the job they are not related to!
First let me put out some of the questions to you now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-you-know-how-difficult-it-is-to-get-a-job-after-studying-engineering&quot;&gt;Do you know how difficult it is to get a job after studying engineering?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though if you get a good job, do you know how difficult it is to sustain in that job?
Do you ever know the level of competition we face studying in mediocre college?
To get job in core is easy but to sustain there for low salary is not easy for middle class students like us. For a fresher, salary in core jobs starts from 6k. Whereas we middle class people study taking educational loans apart from that we also have got other responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me put it simple here, none in this world works for self satisfaction alone. So you people are working in your related fields, would you work for 0 salary? No! Right. The bitter truth is that we all work for money. 
Why it is so bothering you us not working in our own related fields? What cheap happiness you get saying that again and again? Stop under-rating people. Let’s rewind to some time back, there are so many people I know who roamed out there in our age without any concern on family or any objective in life and now judging about us taking up jobs not related to engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s do some approximate calculations.
In Tamil Nadu, there are 552 engineering college. Top rated colleges would have in average of 150students for each branch. In medium rated college 90students and in low rated colleges 60 students. So for each branch in engineering average of 100 students. Total count is (552*100=55200) let’s consider major branches in engineering alone because the number is frightening already: P.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the major branches are EEE, ECE, IT, CSE, MECH, CIVIL which implies (55200*6) 331200 (Tamil Nadu count alone) students per year. Whether they complete their course or not each one of them are in compulsion to find a job which gradually increases the level of competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students who study in top rated colleges are so lucky as they at least get so much of opportunities.
And we people who study in mediocre/ low rated colleges of course gets opportunities for not so core related jobs. I personally attended a job interview where 3000ppl competed with me on the same day. I am pretty sure if you people have faced such a lot of competition you would have fed with life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can raise a question now. “Then why did you choose engineering?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We too have question for you “Why the hell didn’t you explain the scenario for us before?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are only two possibilities.
You have had the same knowledge we have had when we were studying 12th&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(OR)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You people are so eagerly waiting to look at us fail.
Some of us here chose engineering out of interest but sadly we couldn’t take up the job we like due to family situations and lack of opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is actually not a problem until we love the job we do. It’s even worse when we don’t do the job we like as we are already in stress. You have no idea of the stress we face thinking of our future, money paybacks and the worry of us not able to follow the dreams we have due to family situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is really okay if you are not being supportive, at least stop being sarcastic. We are not wasted people, one day we will be more successful than you are as we realise the financial status of our family earlier than you people. Always remember we are all well determined!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>priya_dharsini</name></author><category term="engineering" /><category term="vibes" /><category term="determination" /><summary>Happiness starts with you...</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://rowthiram.com{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;job.jpg&quot;}" /></entry><entry><title>Happiness starts with you</title><link href="http://rowthiram.com/articles/how-to-stay-happy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happiness starts with you" /><published>2017-03-15T13:55:35+05:30</published><updated>2017-03-15T13:55:35+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/articles/how-to-stay-happy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://rowthiram.com/articles/how-to-stay-happy/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-be-happy&quot;&gt;How to be happy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Happiness depends on you not others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You think others influence your happiness.
I can explain it’s not true,
Our brain creates illusion.It’s just we gotta break through that illusion and create illusion which favours us
Let us see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think, that if someone ignores you and you feel sad.. It’s only because you &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; so.
You should start thinking what you want whether you to worry or to be happy.
If you wanna happy you should apparently stop worrying.
You may ask now &lt;em&gt;but how?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start doing things you like. Diverting yourself.Yes you have all the energy, courage to do it.Just believe that you can do it.Stay committed to something, work hard towards it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When your boss scolds for you not being perfect and it makes you worry?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn to the fullest.Neva mind what others judge about you.Because if you are not gonna believe yourself who else would​? Believe that you are the best thing in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning, no one can be perfect.
Committing mistakes is learning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can learn only when you make a mistake.Learning is progress,why would you be sad for moving forward?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You lose someone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I Know it is really hard to overcome this.But we should move forward or else time wld start moving forward.You lost someone which doesn’t imply you lost yourself.you should overcome it.Think everything is for good.Do things you like.Count on the people you still have and be grateful for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Life doesn’t turn up as you expected&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You did everything you can.you did your best so it’s not your mistake.We gotta just accept life as it is. Cherish every moment.Afterall life is too short.You Neva know what will happen next moment.May be one day life would turn up as you wish or you may die the next moment.Nothing is predictable.Just accept the way life is and stop regretting things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don’t create negative vibes which would affect the people around you too. Always remember negative vibes are contagious just like that of positive vibes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;question-is-what-you-choose&quot;&gt;Question is what you choose?&lt;/h1&gt;</content><author><name>priya_dharsini</name></author><category term="happiness" /><category term="vibes" /><category term="self-help" /><summary>Happiness starts with you...</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://rowthiram.com{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;happy.jpg&quot;}" /></entry><entry><title>Smartphone - Indispensible or not?</title><link href="http://rowthiram.com/articles/smartphone_indispensible_or_not/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Smartphone - Indispensible or not?" /><published>2016-11-20T15:27:56+05:30</published><updated>2016-11-20T15:27:56+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/articles/smartphone_indispensible_or_not</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://rowthiram.com/articles/smartphone_indispensible_or_not/">&lt;p&gt;Smart phones like any other technology aid to the comfort of human beings.
As the name suggests, they are ‘smart ‘ , in the sense they have their own intelligence which allow user’s wit to take  back seat in dealing with day- today chores.
Adding to the comfort, they have made things go ‘instant’ too.
This has been made possible through the development of various applications popularly known as ‘apps’.
There are multiple apps available for a specific purpose, be it messaging or a cab service. I shall not get into this because we are well aware of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, they have brought comfort on our finger tips. And not just the comfort, they have done a real work in sociery upliftment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this trend will go on. It is growing at a pace we are not even able to realize .But we have to pause our tech driven life game and contemplate. Have these devices occupied an irreplaceable corner of our existence or is it just enslavement? In other words, can we really not survive without them or is it just a habit or say a comfort zone we have created for ourselves?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has nothing to do with our increased dependency on smart devices and sorts. The glitch with our tech friendly life is the changing companionship. The very nature of human beings allows them to interact with one another and derive pleasure out of each other’s presence. These devices have evolved into ‘smart’ to enhance and ease that experience.  Instead, they are being employed more as a substitute than a means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we crave more for virtual attention than an actual human companion. We communicate but do not talk. We are connected with ones who are far away but oblivious of our own surrounding.  We have been so severely paralyzed by them that we are incapable of catering an undivided attention to our immediate environment.  From just exterminating loneliness in one’s life, smartphones are invading the personal relationship that people share with one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concern is, it is us, the master of all technologies who allows them to overpower our priorities.  No doubt, smart phones have proven to be the best assistants but should not colonize our personal space.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>krutika_kumari</name></author><category term="smartphone" /><category term="indispensible" /><category term="technology" /><category term="boon" /><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://rowthiram.com{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;smartphone.jpg&quot;}" /></entry><entry><title>Why everyone deserves A LISTENER?</title><link href="http://rowthiram.com/articles/why-everyone-deserves-a-listener/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why everyone deserves A LISTENER?" /><published>2016-11-19T16:55:35+05:30</published><updated>2016-11-19T16:55:35+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/articles/why-everyone-deserves-a-listener</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://rowthiram.com/articles/why-everyone-deserves-a-listener/">&lt;p&gt;In this fast growing world, there is no time for anyone to speak or share upon their feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to share a success story about a girl who always longed for a listener &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may think what is so special about finding a listener? Or what is going to change if you have anyone to listen to you? Actually it makes a hell a lot of difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me begin this story!
A girl named is Tina (Imaginary of coourse :P). Tina is a kind of girl who thinks a lot. She observes every small thing around her and starts thinking about it. She thinks about life, movies, love, physics, stars, philosophy, programming, etc. and keeps everything inside herself because when she tries to share her thoughts with people, they either don’t have time for her or pretends as if they are hearing to what she says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know now you may think, what is so sad about not having a listener.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Having a listener is like a stress buster&lt;/em&gt;, it also satisfies your soul. Tina being in her young age already gone through many unfortunate happenings, (I would share about that in my next article) wanted to come out of it. Speak out to people because talking is the best therapy. Of course she had friends but they were busy with their own life and she couldn’t blame upon them either because that’s all about life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People run behind things and forget to live their moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, she met a guy (DON’T ASK ME HOW). A new person in her life both started to share upon their interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Him: I like to speak about a lot of things ranging from physics till business, but I don’t find anyone to hear them. You know as it is nerdy-nerdy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tina: I hear to people. I like doing that so that they will hear to me.
(Hahaha yeah it was like a pick up line). **&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And they started to speak, speak, speak and yet have some more topics to be spoken on.
Actually, she was the one who was speaking continuously. She spoke everything what came to her mind. She has never been so comfortable with anyone to speak all her mind out.
The way he nods, the way he listens to her encouraged her to speak more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One should be blessed to have any such listener. It makes us to feel contended.
One thing I want to say is to be available to people, listen to them. When your mom shares her daily troubles listen to her, many of us ignore that. Listen to them; listen to anyone who shares about their feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe me it makes them feel better. Help them to feel better. For SOME, IT ACTUALLY SATISFIES THEIR SOUL.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>priya_dharsini</name></author><category term="listener" /><category term="life" /><category term="philosophy" /><summary>What is so special about finding a listener? Or what is going to change if you have anyone to listen to you?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://rowthiram.com{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;so-simple-sample-image-1.jpg&quot;}" /></entry><entry><title>Styling will_paginate using bootstrap themes in rails</title><link href="http://rowthiram.com/articles/styling-will-paginate-using-bootstrap-in-rails/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Styling will_paginate using bootstrap themes in rails" /><published>2016-11-17T01:14:11+05:30</published><updated>2016-11-17T01:14:11+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/articles/styling-will-paginate-using-bootstrap-in-rails</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://rowthiram.com/articles/styling-will-paginate-using-bootstrap-in-rails/">&lt;p&gt;Implemented pagination in rails using will_paginate, struggling to design it beautifully but stuck with tradtional UI. Many gems js plugins are there, but confused on what to use and should work out in first go. There is an amazing gem which will solve your problem in minutes. &lt;a href=&quot;https://rubygems.org/gems/will_paginate-bootstrap&quot;&gt;will_paginate-bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; makes your task very easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we will see how to style our pagination using will_paginate-bootstrap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add required gem to your Gemfile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gem&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;will_paginate-bootstrap&#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and run this in your command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-shell highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;bundle install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, its time to expeience the real magic. If you have a variable &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@posts&lt;/code&gt;, which your are using for pagination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &amp;lt;%= will_paginate @posts, renderer: BootstrapPagination::Rails %&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everything goes successfully, you will get something like this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pagination_result.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For changing colors or design you have to override some defined classes. For example, to change the
color of text written in block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-css highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.pagination&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;li&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;red&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly we can override everything defined under the class &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pagination&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been tested with rails 4+ and rails 5+.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading it out. If it has worked for you. Don’t forget to ‘Share’.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>shilpi_agrawal</name></author><category term="will_paginate" /><category term="bootstrap" /><category term="rails" /><category term="UI" /><category term="styling" /><summary>Give a beautiful UI to will_paginate in rails.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://rowthiram.com{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;pagination.jpg&quot;}" /></entry><entry><title>Impact of demonetization on the life of Indian Businessmans.</title><link href="http://rowthiram.com/articles/impact-of-demonetization-on-the-life-of-indian-businessman/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Impact of demonetization on the life of Indian Businessmans." /><published>2016-11-11T20:54:41+05:30</published><updated>2016-11-11T20:54:41+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/articles/impact-of-demonetization-on-the-life-of-indian-businessman</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://rowthiram.com/articles/impact-of-demonetization-on-the-life-of-indian-businessman/">&lt;p&gt;Time has come for the historical reforms of the economy of India. I feel it is a one life time boldest movements by the Government of India. This scheme is going to impact the businesses, the Aam Admi, and financial institutions – all at some level or the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The driving force behind this historical decision was to eradicate black money. A recent study had pegged India’s black market economy at over Rs 30 lakh crore or about 20 percent of total GDP. This is even bigger than the GDP’s of many countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this move in play, black money holders are left with only option to route this money through banks, declaring it to be their income. You know the after effects, the question arises that how did they earn that income? Their files would be subjected to scrutiny and huge taxes will be applicable. Even if they show this as income in the normal course of business, they will have to pay taxes on it as per current rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let us come to our topic what effects would you find in BLG?? Following consequences/impact may happen and which can be identified:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sudden decrease in Stock: A client can justify Cash deposit by realization of closing stock. There might be a mismatch of the stock in holding.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Realization of Debtors: Debtors will be realized to show cash in their account, which may imply the cash deposited is related to business activity.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sudden increase in Sales: You may see a significant exponential growth in sales prior to cut-off date. (Due to back dated billing).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Unusual increase in profit margin: A client might remove miscellaneous expenses from expenses head so that it will have effect on profit margin and cash in hand.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Unusual increase in other Income: To justify the cash deposited, other income might be there in the name of Income from Tution, Professional Fees, and Commission Income etc.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Gift Income: Cash taken as gift from relatives only, can be easily justified to account the cash deposited.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Steep increase in loan from Relatives: Cash might be deposited in relatives account and from there client can take as a loan.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sale of Jewelry: If there is jewelry in Balance Sheet, cash deposited might be justified with the sale of jewelry.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Credit Summations: Credit summations in the period of October and November can be seen high as compared to other months.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Property Value: Property value is expected to reduce. Further, for enhancement cases, we need to be careful particularly where collateral cover is less than 100%.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Diversion of funds: The locker for black money are the sectors like Jewelry and real estate, now the gates are open where clients have less scope to divert their funds.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>surbhi_agrawal</name></author><category term="500 and 1000 notes" /><category term="demonetization" /><summary>A one life time boldest move by the Government of India.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://rowthiram.com{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;so-simple-sample-image-6.jpg&quot;}" /></entry><entry><title>Women’s Privilege</title><link href="http://rowthiram.com/articles/where-women-are-respected/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Women&#39;s Privilege" /><published>2016-08-02T13:25:35+05:30</published><updated>2016-08-02T13:25:35+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/articles/where-women-are-respected</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://rowthiram.com/articles/where-women-are-respected/">&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Where women are respected, there the gods delight; and where they are not,
 		there all works and efforts come to naught.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After so many years of &lt;em&gt;Equality Talks&lt;/em&gt;,you think women are respected? Do we actually respect women?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, No pressure. Try answering me for this one. Do women really have equal rights? Haan? Now this one, do we atleast know what are some problems faced by any woman?.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first when a girl baby is born, most Indians behave as if its a disgrace as dowry has to be given when she gets married. Dowry makes the difference. A man sells himself for the dowry and also takes away the girl and her dreams with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atleat before marriage, was she actually allowed to follow her dreams?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No! Not in most cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/gandhi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Not every women&#39;s dream is to be married.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically, the first one to suppress a women is another women. When she wants to explore things,they are restricted saying that it is not meant for girls and when she fights her way out of it follows the bigger miseries. The problem starts with stalkers. Every month,there is atleast one news that somewhere a tech girl has been raped or murdered or both. The aftereffect of this, some parents who left their daughter to follow their dreams also start to restrict them. Why? Just why? You don’t know how much we fought for a chance to pursue our dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now comes the buzz word &lt;em&gt;marriage&lt;/em&gt;. Most women choose to stay with their husband despite the assaults they go through. Now why is that? Only because they are afraid of the society and feel this is what was meant for them and is something that cannot be changed. Since her childhood the restrictions and “behave-like-a-girl” has been following her. Parents restricted her from following her dreams, she now has no idea of how to be independent and when she thinks of going back to her parents place also she would be treated as its a big disgrace for their family. So forgetting about her dreams and adjusting to the brutalities ,she starts to live for her husband. Atleast by then is she happy? Naah! There are so many unsaid murders because of dowries, impotence. Since she is not well educated,the cycle repeats.She would now restrict her daughter from following her dreams and the cycle repeats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally, Education and Awareness plays the major role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you educate a woman, you educate a family, if you educate a girl, you educate the future.&lt;/strong&gt; - Queen Rania of Jordan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t blame on the whole society. There are people who support a woman’s growth but still the cruelities continues to happen. We have identified the problem and also the solution.The problem is inequality and the solution is education. Implementation is in our hands,the future generation!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>priya_dharsini</name></author><category term="women" /><category term="empowerment" /><category term="quality" /><summary>Where women are respected, there the gods delight; and where they are not, there all works and efforts come to naught.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://rowthiram.com{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;so-simple-sample-image-2.jpg&quot;}" /></entry><entry><title>5 Business rules on your fingertips.</title><link href="http://rowthiram.com/blog/five-rules-you-should-know-before-starting-your-business/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Business rules on your fingertips." /><published>2016-07-30T13:59:24+05:30</published><updated>2016-07-30T13:59:24+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/blog/five-rules-you-should-know-before-starting-your-business</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://rowthiram.com/blog/five-rules-you-should-know-before-starting-your-business/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;key-points-of-a-business&quot;&gt;KEY POINTS OF A BUSINESS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business is a word which is used as a fashion trend these days and even sometimes referred with a  different name “startup”. People who have money or have a different idea start converting that idea into a product that could be sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But hey people, you missed a very important point there,  business is not just an idea, it’s a long term process, it’s not just a cycle of 1 or 2 years, but it’s a cycle of your whole life and it should continue even after your death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some points which I am going to share today with everyone, which need to be considered before starting any business. It doesn’t matter what type of business it is, either it’s a small turnover business or a big turnover, these points are common for all type of industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lets-see-the-points-now--&quot;&gt;Let’s see the points now :-&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You should have the courage to handle risks:&lt;/strong&gt;  Many times big opportunities will knock your door but it won’t come alone, it will come with lots of risk involved. But If you want to grow your business, you should have the courage to handle them to take those opportunities to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You should be money minded:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s not about being cheap or greedy  but it’s about being a business person, even if your business has turnover of 1 Crore you can’t afford to loose even 1 rupee. There are many businesses which has just one rupee margin over one piece of product. So imagine if you sell 1 crore such product, one day how much will you earn. So, always remember every single penny counts just as every drop matters in making an ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You should always be ready to learn everything:&lt;/strong&gt; In initial stage of your business, you might not be aware of different tasks involved or how much human labour will be needed to complete them. Everyone whoever works for you , they all are employees they won’t take your business as seriously as you do. So you have to be prepared for all ups and downs and you have to be ready to do whatever it takes to take your business forward. An event from my life, my dad owns a business which requires many labourers to load and unload  the truck. Once a labour got sick, who had to unload goods from a truck. My dad couldn’t say to those people to go back home as it would have taken more time to call other labourers and we had to release the truck immediately. But you cannot ask a sick labourer to work, that’s against business ethics. So, finally my dad himself worked as a labourer and helped other labourers in unloading the truck. So, you have to take the responsibility of everything whenever it is needed when you own a business.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have to understand it’s a 24*7 work:&lt;/strong&gt; Everything has definite time no doubt, but remember that there are things which can require your attention anytime and  sometimes it can be your business also. Now, if you own a Datacenter and in the middle of the night you experience some unintended failures, then you can’t be just sleeping you have to wake up in the middle of night and get it fixed. That’s how it works “ with great power comes greater responsibility”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your business should never go to the revenue of zero:&lt;/strong&gt; Last but not the least, the most important point, once your business start making revenues, remember whatever it takes just make sure revenue should never go to zero. If it does, it means it’s a signal that market has stopped showing interest in your business, that’s the point when you need to rework on your business.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For the closing lines I will just give one  advice, whatever you do,  it should solve problem of atleast one person . So before starting with anything always do a good market research.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep making money ;)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>shilpi_agrawal</name></author><category term="business" /><category term="ideas" /><summary>Business is a long term process, it’s not just a cycle of 1 or 2 years, but it’s a cycle of your whole life and it should continue even after your death.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://rowthiram.com{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;business.jpg&quot;}" /></entry><entry><title>Start investing in just 5 minutes.</title><link href="http://rowthiram.com/blog/start-investing-in-stock-market-in-just-5-minutes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Start investing in just 5 minutes." /><published>2016-07-25T13:59:24+05:30</published><updated>2016-07-25T13:59:24+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/blog/start-investing-in-stock-market-in-just-5-minutes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://rowthiram.com/blog/start-investing-in-stock-market-in-just-5-minutes/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;stock-market-investment&quot;&gt;STOCK MARKET INVESTMENT&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are salaried employee and thinking where to invest your money to get the maximum percentage of interest, then you have landed on the right page, investing in share market is the best option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Share market has two things one is trading and another one is investing. If you are looking for longer term and you want to play safe, I would suggest to go with investing, that’s what I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trading:&lt;/strong&gt; Where you buy a share on opening of market and sell on closing of market. This is for professional people, who have full knowledge over the share market. This can be very risky for new players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investing:&lt;/strong&gt; Where you buys one share and keep it, till whenever you want. You must be thinking ,‘how do I get money out of it’ :P.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say, we want to buy one share of Bharti Airtel which is costing Rs 326/- acc. to today’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.S. Before buying any shares first look into their previous graphs and future prediction, it’s for your satisfaction, just for assuring yourself that you are not throwing arrow in dark&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is something called dividend, when any company makes profit after cutting out all their expenses and still hold money and want to give some
profit to their shareholders, they give that money to all of their shareholders based on their shares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I put it in more technical terms &lt;em&gt;“A dividend is a distribution of a portion of a company’s earnings, decided by the board of directors, to a class of its shareholders. Dividends can be issued as cash payments, as shares of stock, or other property.” - Investopedia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, dividend is one source of profit, and another one is your investment getting its valued high, as company grows, share market will also get high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as we all know nothing comes so easy :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only thing you need to do is keeping a closer look on everyday’s market value of that company. Sometimes you can get even 100% rate of interest. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;now-its-time-to-get-our-hands-dirty-for-real-d&quot;&gt;Now its time to get our hands dirty for real :D&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Get your PAN Card ready.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bank A/C ( It’s always good to have a privatised bank account for share market purpose.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Open NSDL demat account &lt;em&gt;OR&lt;/em&gt; open a demat account in  your respective bank.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Find a broker near your area, or there are some banks which provides facility within their bank itself like ICICI Direct. In ICICI direct you don’t need any broker you can invest on your own. You need to have one among these two, to sell or purchase the shares.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hurray! you are good to go.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Write a check in the name of your broker and tell him what share, how many and on what price you want to buy &lt;em&gt;OR&lt;/em&gt; If you have ICICI direct kind of account, you can purchase or sell the shares on your own with just one click.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any doubt about, what share to buy you can always subscribe to CNBC Channel and their daily newspapers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before starting in real, if you like to have some demo kind of thing where you can first try, there are some applications which does that. One of them is moneycontrol which I use personally. Moneycontrol mobile application is really good you can even whish list your company, and you will keep getting notifications about everydays growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>shilpi_agrawal</name></author><category term="stock market" /><category term="investment" /><summary>If you are salaried employee and thinking where to invest your money in, then you have landed to right page.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://rowthiram.com{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;stock-market.jpg&quot;}" /></entry><entry><title>How-to find best discounted products on Amazon.</title><link href="http://rowthiram.com/blog/how-to-find-great-deals-on-amazon/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How-to find best discounted products on Amazon." /><published>2016-07-23T14:55:35+05:30</published><updated>2016-07-23T14:55:35+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/blog/how-to-find-great-deals-on-amazon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://rowthiram.com/blog/how-to-find-great-deals-on-amazon/">&lt;p&gt;How to find great deals on Amazon? Amazon already runs regular campaigns for user benefits. Although there are huge deals in amazon, there is no filter for us to sort the products we like based on the discount available for the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s make use of a simple search element to get products with discounted price. It works on both Amazon.com and Amazon India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a sample screenshot of the search that was performed in Clothing category to get deals with 80-90% discount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/amazon_hack_1.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did I get deals that have 80-90% discount? Yayy! Simple shopping hacks. A very simple search string was used to find the discounted items in the selected category in Amazon site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get to the amazing part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  www.amazon.com/gp/search/?node=nodenumber&amp;amp;pct-off=x-y
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Amazon India&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  www.amazon.in/gp/search/?node=nodenumber&amp;amp;pct-off=x-y
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the main URL that is used search through our selected category for the best discounted products. The URL isn’t ready to use, you need to make slight modifications to the URL as per your requirements. The ‘x’ and ‘y’ at the end of the URL are the parameters that define your discount range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;www.amazon.in/gp/search/?node=nodenumber&amp;amp;pct-off=80-90
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This URL when complete will fetch you all the products with discounts inbetween 80 to 90 percent. We still have to make a slight tweak to the URL to get the result that we wanted, we need to set the category for which we want to apply the discounted search string.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon has a unique node number for each category, which you can find from Amazon URL. A URL that contains nodenumber belonging to Books,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  https://www.amazon.com/books-used-books-textbooks/b/ref=nav_shopall_bo?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;node=283155
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Amazon India&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  http://www.amazon.in/Books/b/ref=sd_allcat_books_all?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;node=976389031
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;node&lt;/strong&gt; parameter in the above URL is the value we need to complete our Amazon shopping hack. Here is a screenshot that gives us the URL with the node number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/amazon_hack_3.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigate to the category you want to purchase from the Amazon site and get a hold of the nodenumber belonging to the category from the URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the node number in the URL that we have, so our final URL looks like this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;www.amazon.in/gp/search/?node=976389031&amp;amp;pct-off=80-90
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a screenshot of the discounted result for above URL,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/amazon_hack_2.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​
Good luck with finding great deals on Amazon, if you do not have any available offers for the search just use different discount values to get more result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay Put. :D&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>preethi_kr</name></author><category term="amazon" /><category term="website" /><category term="deals" /><category term="shopping" /><category term="shopping hacks" /><summary>Simple jugaad that can help you reduce your search for the best deal..</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://rowthiram.com{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;amazon1.jpg&quot;}" /></entry></feed>
