<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://rowthiram.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://rowthiram.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-07-18T11:28:21+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/</id><title>Rowthiram</title><subtitle>Stay Put. A blog trying to keep you engaged.</subtitle><entry><title>Illustrations Vs Words</title><link href="http://rowthiram.com/articles/illustrations-vs-words/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Illustrations Vs Words" /><published>2016-07-15T17:25:35+05:30</published><updated>2016-07-15T17:25:35+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/articles/illustrations-vs-words</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://rowthiram.com/articles/illustrations-vs-words/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;4.5 Billion years ago&lt;/em&gt;, our beautiful Earth, round and blue came into the picture of solar system bundled with uniqueness talking for itself. A little later life found it’s way a few billion years later. Evolution took us for a ride bringing us to this point in time. Looking back to the early stages of human, there was some thing that was missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;what-was-it-not-sure&quot;&gt;What was it? Not Sure?&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Communication&lt;/em&gt;, without which life would be really boring. Now, we communicate using words but what about some million years ago?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No alphabets. No words. Yet our ancestors managed to survive without words for communication. Isn’t that something amazing to even think about. :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how did they communicate? How?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;umm-illustrations&quot;&gt;Umm, Illustrations.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our ancestors communicated with their neighbours using illustrations. What is Illustration? Now stop thinking technically. :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its nothing but the action or means of illustrating something. Doesn’t stop with just that. Hmm, It also mean as expressing by as Drawings or Designs. Cool. Ain’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old sculptures, statues, art works always stand an epitome for how cool communication was earlier. The beautiful and intricate Illustrations in it shows us Illustration was the main key for communication those days. It made people understand things easily and it also helped the differently abled(deaf and dumb) to not really think themselves any lesser people. But, as days and years passed with technological advancements people started to forget the beauty in communication using Illustrations. I see people using more of words to communicate and not the illustrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel so bad to see the world putting an end to a beautiful art of communication. If Illustration was the key for communication in 2016 and not words , there is absolutely no need for any languages or translators to communicate. It would have made world more united and simple to survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Words are just too complicated. Are they not? By the way, too ambuiguous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case, Ha ha ! I use more of words but I always wanted illustrations to be my primary source of communication. It gives me more knowledge and deepens my ability to understand things with ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you think the same way? Let me know. :D&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>venkat_subish</name></author><category term="language" /><category term="communication" /><category term="words" /><category term="interaction" /><summary>Illustrations or Words,making communication simple and beautiful?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://rowthiram.com{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;so-simple-sample-image-5.jpg&quot;}" /></entry><entry><title>Employee Referral</title><link href="http://rowthiram.com/articles/employee-referral/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Employee Referral" /><published>2016-07-15T16:55:35+05:30</published><updated>2016-07-15T16:55:35+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/articles/employee-referral</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://rowthiram.com/articles/employee-referral/">&lt;p&gt;Employee referrals are few of the most cost effective ways of employee recruitment and the best means to build man power required by the organization. Employee Referral is a simple internal recruitment method to interview and hire more employees through the referrals provided by their existing employees. Even though there are many ways for recruiting employee, 40% of companies opt for referral recruiting and you know why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the top 6 reasons why companies recruit people by reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;save-time&quot;&gt;SAVE TIME!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timing is everything. The recruitment process is small and easy than compared with other methods of recruiting and also people hired by reference start their new position sooner than their counterparts. Referred hires have job satisfaction and stay in the job for longer than the other recruiters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;save-money&quot;&gt;SAVE MONEY!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Referral recruitment is the cheapest way for recruiting so economically it is the best way for recruitment. The company would always go for the way which is economically best&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quality-is-important&quot;&gt;QUALITY IS IMPORTANT&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the respondents feel that the referral recruiting is the best way for finding the best quality employee. With the increased demand for quality service and products, it has become important for companies to hire more skilled and productive employees. Research has shown that the employees who are hired through the various referral schemes are significantly better and more efficient than the ones hired through the other channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;compatible&quot;&gt;COMPATIBLE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Referred hires fit the company culture and values better because the referral already knows one of the employee and the company already. As the candidates who apply through other channels can be from any locality, or field of work, there are higher possibilities of them not being accustomed to the organization’s work environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;immediate-results&quot;&gt;IMMEDIATE RESULTS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the growing unemployment and the demand for a more skilled workforce, employees are the best way of finding some quick leads and almost double the number of hires within a year. The referral bonuses are often lucrative and lead to a higher employee satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a quick and easy way of generating more and more candidates to hire within your organization, employee referral scheme is certainly the best tactic that you can opt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trust-is-all-that-matters&quot;&gt;TRUST IS ALL THAT MATTERS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The employee knows the referral already thus the company would have full trust on the person through referral recruitment because even when the referral cheats the company or any misbehavior tends to happen still the person could be caught through the referred employee&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>priya_dharsini</name></author><category term="employee-referral" /><category term="readability" /><category term="quality" /><summary>Why employee referrals?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://rowthiram.com{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;so-simple-sample-image-7.jpg&quot;}" /></entry><entry><title>Welcome to Rowthiram</title><link href="http://rowthiram.com/articles/welcome-to-rowthiram/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Rowthiram" /><published>2016-07-14T16:55:35+05:30</published><updated>2016-07-14T16:55:35+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/articles/welcome-to-rowthiram</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://rowthiram.com/articles/welcome-to-rowthiram/">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Rowthiram!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rowthiram&quot;&gt;Rowthiram&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rowthiram is an initiative to bring in the most recent happenings in Technology. We would be updating the site continuously with more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would also be rolling out many new tutorials and how-to posts to keep you updated over the happenings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay Put.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,
Team Rowthiram&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>preethi_kr</name></author><summary>Welcome to Rowthiram!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://rowthiram.com{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;so-simple-sample-image-5.jpg&quot;}" /></entry></feed>
