<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://rowthiram.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://rowthiram.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-07-22T18:23:32+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/</id><title>Rowthiram</title><subtitle>Stay Put. A blog trying to keep you engaged.</subtitle><entry><title>How-To Install Ubuntu.</title><link href="http://rowthiram.com/blog/how-to-install-ubuntu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How-To Install Ubuntu." /><published>2016-07-20T16:55:35+05:30</published><updated>2016-07-20T16:55:35+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/blog/how-to-install-ubuntu</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://rowthiram.com/blog/how-to-install-ubuntu/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ubuntu-installation&quot;&gt;UBUNTU INSTALLATION&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Ubuntu is one of the widely used Linux distros, getting your hands on it is a must-know thing for most people entering the software field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of different ways of installing Ubuntu. In this guid I’m gonna walk you through one such way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu can be installed in various scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You may install Ubuntu on a computer with no operating system at all.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You may install Ubuntu with some other operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also installing Ubuntu with other operating system,(also termed dual-booting) there are various ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Install Ubuntu from USB Stick.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Install it using Virtual Machine.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Install it using wubi installer i.e. especially designed for Windows 8.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post we will see how to install dual boot Ubuntu alongside another operating system, in our case it’s Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s begin. :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;download-and-get-ready&quot;&gt;Download and Get Ready:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download Ubuntu:&lt;/strong&gt; Download your preferred version of Ubuntu such as Ubuntu 14.04, 15.10, 16.04 and there’s a lot more versions, latest being 16.04. You can easily get any of its versions just by clicking here. Download time of this huge file of more than 1GB totally depends on your bandwidth speed. If your on BSNL, we’re on the same boat. :P&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Burn your CD or create a boot able USB stick:&lt;/strong&gt; For this step you need software which is designed especially for Ubuntu i.e. .Universal USB Installer. There are a lot more installers to solve this purpose, this is more promising.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Configure your BIOS&lt;/strong&gt;. Enter your systems boot settings(BIOS) and set boot order option. Entering Boot settings various between various models, so google to find the key to enter the Boot settings.So, whenever your computer starts, press the BIOS key. My case it was - F2 Key.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Plug in your USB stick/Live CD and restart the machine. After entering to the setup, select the device you want to boot: - live CD or USB stick. The installer will automatically take you to this screen.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;figure&gt;
     &lt;img style=&quot;margin-left: 15%;&quot; src=&quot;/images/ubuntu_install_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Whether you want to install it or try it, you will have to follow the same procedures.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;After booting from your live CD or USB, you will get to the Try or Install window. Before you start the installation, make sure your computer is connected to the Internet. If your network connection is not working, Click Try Ubuntu and let it load. Then go to the top right&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt; ** Click on the gear icon -&amp;gt; select System settings -&amp;gt; Additional Drivers -&amp;gt; it will search for the drivers for the network adapter -&amp;gt; click on the drivers to install -&amp;gt; then from the Desktop select Install Ubuntu. **
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Before beginning the installation, system will need three necessary things.
     1. Connection to the power source.
     2. Connection to the network.
     3. At least 4.8 GB free in your hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;figure&gt;
     &lt;img style=&quot;margin-left: 15%;&quot; src=&quot;/images/ubuntu_install_2.1.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;You can proceed when you have all these set up, although the first two are not absolutely necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For installation you will have three options in dialog box, select third option. i.e. Something else. Select it and click Install Now. We’re almost Done, but coming next is the tricky part.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;figure&gt;
     &lt;img style=&quot;margin-left: 15%;&quot; src=&quot;/images/ubuntu_install_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;While installation is going on you’ll get the information about your unallocated space and allocated space. Select one of the unallocated space in which you want to install Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;figure&gt;
     &lt;img style=&quot;margin-left: 15%;&quot; src=&quot;/images/ubuntu_install_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, this is where you are going to instruct the machine about the memory settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We need to create three partitions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Select the unallocated space or drive, click on (+) , a new dialog box will appear. In the drop down menu select swap area and the size will depend on your RAM size. i.e 1GB of Swap would be perfect for a system with 4GB RAM. Now, do the Math. :P&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Get back to the same dialog box, press Add. In the drop down menu of the new dialog box, select mount point as /boot and size will be 512 MB.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Again return back to the same dialog box, click Add. In the drop down menu of the new dialog box select mount point as / and size will be rest of the space.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally click on Install, and Ubuntu will start installing on your system. The progress will be shown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proceed to configue Time and Network settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes! We installed Ubuntu. Now start playing with it. Have Fun!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>shilpi_agrawal</name></author><category term="dual-boot" /><category term="ubuntu" /><category term="os" /><summary>Ubuntu is Linux based open source operating system which is basically designed for programming addicts.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://rowthiram.com{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;ubuntu.jpg&quot;}" /></entry><entry><title>My First Job Experience</title><link href="http://rowthiram.com/articles/my-first-job-experience/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My First Job Experience" /><published>2016-07-18T13:55:35+05:30</published><updated>2016-07-18T13:55:35+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/articles/my-first-job-experience</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://rowthiram.com/articles/my-first-job-experience/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just another regular 2016 passout with much hopes in life, I found a new side of myself in this journey of 2 months.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a fresher,I joined an IT company as a software trainee.Since I am from EEE department,I was little nervous thinking whether I could survive in the company.Unlike other IT companies,Here for few weeks they thought us how to analyse a problem.After we came to an understanding of how to analyse a problem,the next phase of training started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-phase&quot;&gt;FIRST PHASE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A project requirement was kept in front of us.It was to create a web application for recruiting process.It consisted of  four modules such as generic module,HR module,Jobseeker module and Employee module.It was then split among 10 of us and we started to work on it.
At first I didn’t feel any difficulty as the first step was to analyse the requirement,prepare BRD,FSD,wireframes and get approval from the client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;second-phase&quot;&gt;SECOND PHASE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second phase was UI design training.The trainer taught us in such a way that the training was so interesting and it kept us committed.HTML and CSS was new to me.I started to learn every day and started to try it practically.I was keep on experimenting unti I came to an understanding.By then ,we 10 of us were clear about basics of HTML and CSS.We started to design our pages as per our wireframes using bootstrap.First we were trained with plain html and then we were taught about bootstrap such that we felt easy and was very clear  about the basics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure style=&quot;margin-left:20%;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/priya_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Yes! I made it.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;third-phase&quot;&gt;THIRD PHASE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third phase was validation before the datas hit the database.They taught us javascript and Jquery.I found it  very interesting because with Jquery we can do wonders without making the page reload.Ajax concept was so cool such that we can call upon a function using url without reloading
the page.Jquery effects,traversing functions and much more functions.It was very interesting such that we tried making tabs,accordion on our own.Untill then everything went cool and I enjoyed learning these and also felt easy implementing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fourth-phase&quot;&gt;FOURTH PHASE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we completing validations.We were into the php training.Our pages were put into mvc architecture(Model View Controller).We created tables in mysql as defined in FSD and then started work on functionalities.The trainer taught us how to make a login page,some of the php functions,session and cookies.We had test on every Monday for four weeks.First three weeks it was theoritical and it consisted of logical questions.Some how we cleared our tests.I learnt how to use html inside php code and vice versa.PHP is like an ocean when we start exploring it,we start to realise how interesting the langauge is.All we have to do is get involved with it,start exploring it.When I first joined this company,I didn’t even know to define a class,method and declare a variable also.Now i have confidence,that i can create a web application on my own.Debugging an error in php is also an interesting factor.We learnt to use firebug,check page source and rectify the errors.Now the fourth phase has also been completed successfully and the journey with the company continues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m gonna be sharing more of my posts until the world knows me. Stay connected. Cheers! :D&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>priya_dharsini</name></author><category term="employee" /><category term="diary" /><category term="programming" /><summary>Finding out a whole new myself. Just another regular 2016 passout with much hopes in life, I found a new side of myself in this journey of 2 months...</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://rowthiram.com{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;my_first_job.jpg&quot;}" /></entry><entry><title>Illustrations Vs Words</title><link href="http://rowthiram.com/articles/illustrations-vs-words/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Illustrations Vs Words" /><published>2016-07-15T17:25:35+05:30</published><updated>2016-07-15T17:25:35+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/articles/illustrations-vs-words</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://rowthiram.com/articles/illustrations-vs-words/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;4.5 Billion years ago&lt;/em&gt;, our beautiful Earth, round and blue came into the picture of solar system bundled with uniqueness talking for itself. A little later life found it’s way a few billion years later. Evolution took us for a ride bringing us to this point in time. Looking back to the early stages of human, there was some thing that was missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;what-was-it-not-sure&quot;&gt;What was it? Not Sure?&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Communication&lt;/em&gt;, without which life would be really boring. Now, we communicate using words but what about some million years ago?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No alphabets. No words. Yet our ancestors managed to survive without words for communication. Isn’t that something amazing to even think about. :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how did they communicate? How?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;umm-illustrations&quot;&gt;Umm, Illustrations.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our ancestors communicated with their neighbours using illustrations. What is Illustration? Now stop thinking technically. :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its nothing but the action or means of illustrating something. Doesn’t stop with just that. Hmm, It also mean as expressing by as Drawings or Designs. Cool. Ain’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old sculptures, statues, art works always stand an epitome for how cool communication was earlier. The beautiful and intricate Illustrations in it shows us Illustration was the main key for communication those days. It made people understand things easily and it also helped the differently abled(deaf and dumb) to not really think themselves any lesser people. But, as days and years passed with technological advancements people started to forget the beauty in communication using Illustrations. I see people using more of words to communicate and not the illustrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel so bad to see the world putting an end to a beautiful art of communication. If Illustration was the key for communication in 2016 and not words , there is absolutely no need for any languages or translators to communicate. It would have made world more united and simple to survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Words are just too complicated. Are they not? By the way, too ambuiguous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case, Ha ha ! I use more of words but I always wanted illustrations to be my primary source of communication. It gives me more knowledge and deepens my ability to understand things with ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you think the same way? Let me know. :D&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>venkat_subish</name></author><category term="language" /><category term="communication" /><category term="words" /><category term="interaction" /><summary>Illustrations or Words,making communication simple and beautiful? Words are just too complicated. Are they not? By the way, too ambuiguous...</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://rowthiram.com{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;venkat1.jpg&quot;}" /></entry><entry><title>Employee Referral</title><link href="http://rowthiram.com/articles/employee-referral/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Employee Referral" /><published>2016-07-15T16:55:35+05:30</published><updated>2016-07-15T16:55:35+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/articles/employee-referral</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://rowthiram.com/articles/employee-referral/">&lt;p&gt;Employee referrals are few of the most cost effective ways of employee recruitment and the best means to build man power required by the organization. Employee Referral is a simple internal recruitment method to interview and hire more employees through the referrals provided by their existing employees. Even though there are many ways for recruiting employee, 40% of companies opt for referral recruiting and you know why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the top 6 reasons why companies recruit people by reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;save-time&quot;&gt;SAVE TIME!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timing is everything. The recruitment process is small and easy than compared with other methods of recruiting and also people hired by reference start their new position sooner than their counterparts. Referred hires have job satisfaction and stay in the job for longer than the other recruiters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;save-money&quot;&gt;SAVE MONEY!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Referral recruitment is the cheapest way for recruiting so economically it is the best way for recruitment. The company would always go for the way which is economically best&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quality-is-important&quot;&gt;QUALITY IS IMPORTANT&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the respondents feel that the referral recruiting is the best way for finding the best quality employee. With the increased demand for quality service and products, it has become important for companies to hire more skilled and productive employees. Research has shown that the employees who are hired through the various referral schemes are significantly better and more efficient than the ones hired through the other channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;compatible&quot;&gt;COMPATIBLE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Referred hires fit the company culture and values better because the referral already knows one of the employee and the company already. As the candidates who apply through other channels can be from any locality, or field of work, there are higher possibilities of them not being accustomed to the organization’s work environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;immediate-results&quot;&gt;IMMEDIATE RESULTS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the growing unemployment and the demand for a more skilled workforce, employees are the best way of finding some quick leads and almost double the number of hires within a year. The referral bonuses are often lucrative and lead to a higher employee satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a quick and easy way of generating more and more candidates to hire within your organization, employee referral scheme is certainly the best tactic that you can opt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trust-is-all-that-matters&quot;&gt;TRUST IS ALL THAT MATTERS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The employee knows the referral already thus the company would have full trust on the person through referral recruitment because even when the referral cheats the company or any misbehavior tends to happen still the person could be caught through the referred employee&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>priya_dharsini</name></author><category term="employee-referral" /><category term="readability" /><category term="quality" /><summary>Why employee referrals? Here are the top 6 reasons why companies recruit people by reference...</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://rowthiram.com{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;referral.png&quot;}" /></entry><entry><title>Welcome to Rowthiram.</title><link href="http://rowthiram.com/articles/welcome-to-rowthiram/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Rowthiram." /><published>2016-07-14T16:55:35+05:30</published><updated>2016-07-14T16:55:35+05:30</updated><id>http://rowthiram.com/articles/welcome-to-rowthiram</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://rowthiram.com/articles/welcome-to-rowthiram/">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Rowthiram!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rowthiram&quot;&gt;Rowthiram&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rowthiram is an initiative to bring in the most recent happenings in Technology. We would be updating the site continuously with more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would also be rolling out many new tutorials and how-to posts to keep you updated over the happenings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay Put.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,
Team Rowthiram&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>preethi_kr</name></author><summary>Welcome to Rowthiram!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://rowthiram.com{&quot;feature&quot;=&gt;&quot;198H.jpg&quot;}" /></entry></feed>
